Hirsh Health Sciences Library Records UA225
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Slide library, 1893 -- 1998; UA225.004; 1.2 Linear Feet; 937 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains slides created and collected by Dr. Henry H. Banks as part of his research for his historical book celebrating the centennial of the School of Medicine, "A Century of Excellence: The History of Tufts University School of Medicine 1893-1993." There are images of the School of Medicine, its staff and students. There are also slides highlighting statistics about the School tuition, enrollment, loans, and financial aid from the 1980s and 1990s.
  This series is arranged as found.
  - Medical School Facilities, Veterinary School and Medford Campus, 1893 -- 1987; UA225.004.001.00001; Tufts University School of Medicine
    - Anatomy at 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00001; Tufts University (Box 1)
      In a (class)room
      Boston (Mass.); Buildings; Slides (photographs)
    - Pathology - Dr.MacMahon and students at Huntington Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00002; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom, dissecting
      Boston (Mass.); Pathology; Faculty, Medical; Slides (photographs); MacMahon, H. Edward
    - Pathology - Dr.MacMahon and students at Huntington Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00003; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom, microscopes
    - Pathology teaching at Huntington Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00004; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom, five people at one microscope
      Boston (Mass.); Pathology; Medical education; Medical students; Slides (photographs)
    - Biochemistry teaching, 1957; UA225.004.001.00001.00005; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Students in lab
      Biochemistry; Medical education; Medical students; Slides (photographs)
    - Anesthesia teaching by Dr. Etsten, UA225.004.001.00001.00006; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Students and teacher in lab
      Anesthesiology; Medical education; Faculty, Medical; Slides (photographs); Etsten, Benjamin E.
    - Anesthesia teaching, 1957; UA225.004.001.00001.00007; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom, with patient or cadaver
      Anesthesiology; Medical education; Slides (photographs)
    - Anesthesia teaching, 1957; UA225.004.001.00001.00008; Tufts University (Box 1)
      With patient
    - Ophthalmology teaching, 1950; UA225.004.001.00001.00009; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Ophthalmology; Medical education; Faculty, Medical; Slides (photographs)
    - Anesthesia teaching of the past, UA225.004.001.00001.00010; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Anesthesiology; Medical education; Faculty, Medical; Slides (photographs)
    - Stearns Auditorium at NEMC, 1950; UA225.004.001.00001.00011; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Students in classroom
      Boston (Mass.); Auditoriums; Medical students; Slides (photographs); New England Medical Center
    - Patten Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00012; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom with students
      Boston (Mass.); Auditoriums; Medical students; Slides (photographs)
    - Physiology department - Huntington Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00013; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Classroom, empty
      Boston (Mass.); Physiology; Education; Laboratories; Slides (photographs)
    - Tufts Medford campus - Tisch Library, UA225.004.001.00001.00014; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside on green, looking at building, with students
      Medford (Mass.); Tufts University. Libraries; Slides (photographs); Tisch Library; Medford Campus
    - Report of Committee to Establish TUSM, 1893-08-15; UA225.004.001.00001.00015; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Letter
      Boston (Mass.); Tufts University. School of Medicine; Slides (photographs); Tufts College Medical School
    - First Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1893; UA225.004.001.00001.00016; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Buildings; Slides (photographs); Tufts College Medical School
    - First Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1893; UA225.004.001.00001.00017; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside looking from street to buildings, horse-drawn carriages
    - First Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1893; UA225.004.001.00001.00018; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - First Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1893; UA225.004.001.00001.00019; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Plaque at site of the first building - Tufts College Medical School, UA225.004.001.00001.00020; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Two people are in picture
      Boston (Mass.); Signs and signboards; Plaques and plaquettes; Slides (photographs); Tufts College Medical School
    - Second Building - Tufts College Medical School, UA225.004.001.00001.00021; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Building, far view, trolley in front
    - Second Building - Tufts College Medical School, UA225.004.001.00001.00022; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Third Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1897; UA225.004.001.00001.00023; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside
    - Third Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1897; UA225.004.001.00001.00024; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Fourth Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1901; UA225.004.001.00001.00025; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Fourth Building - Tufts College Medical School, 1901; UA225.004.001.00001.00026; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00027; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00028; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00029; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00030; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00031; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00032; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Medical and Veterinary Building - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00033; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside entrance
    - Tufts Medical School Entrance - 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00034; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Plaque - Sackler School of Biomedical Sciences, 1981-10-07; UA225.004.001.00001.00035; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Supported by Arthur M. Sackler, Mortimer D. Sackler, Raymond R. Sackler
      Boston (Mass.); Signs and signboards; Plaques and plaquettes; Arthur M. Sackler; Mortimer D. Sackler; Raymond R. Sackler; Slides (photographs)
    - Old Library at 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00036; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Inside, people at tables
      Boston (Mass.); Tufts University. Libraries; Medical libraries; Slides (photographs)
    - Old Library at 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00037; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Old Library at 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00038; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Old Library at 136 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00039; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Inside, person at table
    - Posner Hall sign, UA225.004.001.00001.00040; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside, in front of building
      Boston (Mass.); Signs and signboards; Slides (photographs)
    - Posner Hall, UA225.004.001.00001.00041; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Building
    - Posner Hall, 1983-01-12; UA225.004.001.00001.00042; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside, building
    - Posner Hall lounge, 1958; UA225.004.001.00001.00043; Tufts University (Box 1)
      People sitting in lounge
    - 193 and 203 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00044; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center for Health Communications, UA225.004.001.00001.00045; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Drawing
    - Sackler Building entrance, UA225.004.001.00001.00046; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Entrance halls; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler Center sign, UA225.004.001.00001.00047; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Sign is behind a fence
    - Parking lot - Harrison Ave. (Sackler Center for Health Communications), UA225.004.001.00001.00048; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Parking lots; Slides (photographs)
    - St. James Church - Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00049; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Churches; Construction projects; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler Center construction begins, UA225.004.001.00001.00050; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Next to church
      Boston (Mass.); Construction projects; Architecture; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler Center site, 1983-11; UA225.004.001.00001.00051; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Construction
    - Pouring foundation for the Sackler Center, 1984-02; UA225.004.001.00001.00052; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Building; Foundations; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler Center construction, 1984-04-23; UA225.004.001.00001.00053; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center construction, UA225.004.001.00001.00054; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center construction, UA225.004.001.00001.00055; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center construction, 1984-10; UA225.004.001.00001.00056; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00057; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Building seems to be completed
    - Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00058; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00059; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00060; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Building and St. James Church, UA225.004.001.00001.00061; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center, UA225.004.001.00001.00062; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Center - Tufts 145 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00063; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Plaque/sign, dedicated Jean Mayer, Arthur M. Sackler
      Boston (Mass.); Buildings; Mayer, Jean; Sackler, Arthur M.; Slides (photographs)
    - Architects' drawing - Sackler, UA225.004.001.00001.00064; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Sketch of building
      Boston (Mass.); Buildings; Construction projects; Architectural drawing; Slides (photographs)
    - Diagram of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00065; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Diagram of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00066; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler Opening, UA225.004.001.00001.00067; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Front of news article
      Boston (Mass.); Building dedications; Slides (photographs)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00068; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Students and people in auditorium
      Boston (Mass.); Honorary degrees; Slides (photographs)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00069; Tufts University (Box 1)
      In Auditorium
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00070; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00071; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00072; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00073; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00074; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00075; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00076; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Honorary degrees at Sackler opening, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00077; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler auditorium dedication, 1986-02-21; UA225.004.001.00001.00078; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Building dedications; Auditoriums; Slides (photographs)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00079; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Bridge from Sackler to Proger, UA225.004.001.00001.00080; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Tunnel bridge
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00081; Tufts University (Box 1)
      In auditorium, looking at presentation
      Boston (Mass.); Auditoriums; Medical education; Slides (photographs)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00082; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00083; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00084; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00085; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00086; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student lecture - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00087; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Sackler auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00088; Tufts University (Box 1)
      In auditorium, black and white photo
      Boston (Mass.); Auditoriums; Slides (photographs)
    - Library information desk, UA225.004.001.00001.00089; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Two people standing at library desk talking to each other, two librarians sitting at desk
      Library architecture; Medical libraries; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler library information desk, UA225.004.001.00001.00090; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Two people standing at library circulation desk, talking to two librarians
      Boston (Mass.); Library architecture; Medical libraries; Slides (photographs)
    - Tufts Health Sciences Library - Sackler building 145 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00091; Tufts University (Box 1)
      People at library computers, one reading in stacks
    - Callow room, UA225.004.001.00001.00092; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Empty room with desk and portrait
    - Tufts histology class - Sackler building 145 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00093; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Students at desk, with microscopes, some walking around
      Boston (Mass.); Histology; Medical education; Slides (photographs)
    - Histology class - Sackler building, UA225.004.001.00001.00094; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Histology class - Sackler building, UA225.004.001.00001.00095; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Tufts Health Sciences Library - Sackler building 145 Harrison Ave., UA225.004.001.00001.00096; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Library stacks and desks, two people working at desks
      Boston (Mass.); Medical libraries; Slides (photographs)
    - Sackler library, UA225.004.001.00001.00097; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Library stacks (no people)
    - Sackler library, UA225.004.001.00001.00098; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Student carrolls - Sackler library, UA225.004.001.00001.00099; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Empty carrolls, library stacks in background
    - Small group teaching, UA225.004.001.00001.00100; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Six people in room, discussing
      Medical education; Problem-based learning; Slides (photographs)
    - Study session, UA225.004.001.00001.00101; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Seven people in room, discussing; chemistry on blackboard in background
    - Tufts medical classroom teaching, UA225.004.001.00001.00102; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Seven people in room, discussing
      Boston (Mass.); Medical education; Faculty, Medical; Slides (photographs); Harrington, John T.; Branda, Luis; Talamo, Barbara; Sonnenschein, C. (Carlos)
    - Library small study room, UA225.004.001.00001.00103; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Empty, with desks, blackboard, and slide board
      Boston (Mass.); Classrooms; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Small group teaching in Sackler conference room, UA225.004.001.00001.00104; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Nine people in room, discussing
      Boston (Mass.); Medical education; Building; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Sackler conference room, UA225.004.001.00001.00105; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Problem-based learning; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Conference room, UA225.004.001.00001.00106; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Empty room, large desks
      Classrooms; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Drawing of 136 Harrison, UA225.004.001.00001.00107; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Black and white picture of outside of building with small people on ground outside
      Boston (Mass.); Architectural drawing; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Drawing of 136 Harrison with floors added, UA225.004.001.00001.00108; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Color picture of outside building
    - M & V complex - concept C, UA225.004.001.00001.00109; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Simple floor plan, includes Sackler, South Cove, Infill, Arnold, Stearns, and M and V
      Architectural drawing; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Infill building - Tufts Medical School, UA225.004.001.00001.00110; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Black and white picture of outside of building, includes other buildings in surrounding area
      Boston (Mass.); Buildings; Construction projects; Architectural drawing; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - 136 Harrison with floors added, UA225.004.001.00001.00111; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Color picture of outside of building
    - Infill building, UA225.004.001.00001.00112; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Architecture drawing of different floors from side
    - Infill building, UA225.004.001.00001.00113; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Infill building, UA225.004.001.00001.00114; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Above view map of health sciences campus
    - Proposed international building - Herald Street, UA225.004.001.00001.00115; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Buildings; Construction projects; Maps; Slides (photographs); Boston Campus
    - Infill building - TUSM, UA225.004.001.00001.00116; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Horse arthroscopy - Grafton, UA225.004.001.00001.00117; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Horse and five medical professionals
      Veterinary arthroscopy; Tufts University. School of Veterinary Medicine; Slides (photographs); Grafton Campus; School of Veterinary Medicine
    - Vet School Grafton, UA225.004.001.00001.00118; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Photo of outside of building.
      Grafton (Mass.: Town); Veterinary medicine -- Study and teaching; Tufts University. School of Veterinary Medicine; Slides (photographs); Grafton Campus; School of Veterinary Medicine
    - Vet School Grafton, UA225.004.001.00001.00119; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Two people in outside cage with hawk.
      Grafton (Mass.: Town); Tufts University. School of Veterinary Medicine; Slides (photographs); Grafton Campus; School of Veterinary Medicine
    - Tufts Medford campus, UA225.004.001.00001.00120; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Photo of greenery outside, people sitting on grass
      Medford (Mass.); Tufts University. Libraries; Slides (photographs); Medford campus; Tisch Library
    - Tufts Medford campus, UA225.004.001.00001.00121; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Photo of building, people outside, one dog
      Medford (Mass.); College campuses; Slides (photographs); Medford campus
    - Tufts Medford campus, UA225.004.001.00001.00122; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Photo of entrance of building, people looking at camera on front steps
      Medford (Mass.); College campuses; Slides (photographs); Medford campus; Ballou Hall
    - Tufts Medford campus, UA225.004.001.00001.00123; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Person reading on grass outside, building faintly visible in background
      Medford (Mass.); Slides (photographs); Medford campus; Tisch Library
    - Instruments for Comparative Suddenness of Stimulus, UA225.004.001.00001.00124; Tufts University (Box 1)
      [Comparative Suddenness of Stimulus]?, equipment
      Boston (Mass.); Electrophysiology--instrumentation; Slides (photographs)
    - Physiology department - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00125; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Lab, one person working
    - Physiology department - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00126; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology department - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00127; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Lab
    - Physiology department - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00128; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology cold room, 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00129; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00130; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00131; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00132; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00133; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00134; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00135; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Lab, boxes "Kenmore refrigerator", "Kenmore Freezer"
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00136; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Physiology - 136 Harrison Ave., 1987-01; UA225.004.001.00001.00137; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Lab, two people working
    - Opening of Sackler, Faculty Dining Room, UA225.004.001.00001.00138; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, Faculty Dining Room, UA225.004.001.00001.00139; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, Faculty Dining Room, UA225.004.001.00001.00140; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Empty dining room with set up tables
    - Opening of Sackler, External view of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00141; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Outside of Building
    - Opening of Sackler, External view of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00142; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, External view of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00143; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, External view of Sackler Building, UA225.004.001.00001.00144; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00145; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Auditorium
    - Opening of Sackler, Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00146; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00147; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Boston (Mass.); Auditoriums; DeBlois Auditorium; Slides (photographs)
    - Opening of Sackler, Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00148; Tufts University (Box 1)
    - Opening of Sackler, Auditorium, UA225.004.001.00001.00149; Tufts University (Box 1)
  - Medical Students, Curriculum, Tuition, Financial Aid, Match and Commencement, 1929 -- 1993; UA225.004.001.00002; Tufts University School of Medicine
    - Medical students, UA225.004.001.00002.00001; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Medical students; Slides (photographs)
    - applicants and acceptances, 1960 -- 1988; UA225.004.001.00002.00002; Tufts University (Box 1)
      AAMC Graph
      Universities and colleges--Applications; Medical colleges--Admission; Slides (photographs)
    - Men and women applicants, 1960 -- 1988; UA225.004.001.00002.00003; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Universities and colleges--Applications; Gender; Slides (photographs)
    - Number of medical school applicants and matriculants by sex, 1967 -- 1989; UA225.004.001.00002.00004; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Universities and colleges--Applications; Gender; Medical education--Statistics; Slides (photographs)
    - Application activity over a 20 year period, 1963 -- 1984; UA225.004.001.00002.00005; Tufts University (Box 1)
      Universities and colleges--Applications; Medical education--Statistics; Slides (photographs)